Preliminary Inventory to the Eric Erickson Papers, 1963-1990
Hoover Institution Archives
Eric Erickson Papers
1963-1990
84011
Hoover Institution Archives
18 manuscript boxes (7.5 linear feet)
Correspondence, memoranda, notes, bulletins, newsletters, clippings, and serial issues, relating to the 1963 coup overthrowing President Ngô Dình Diêm in South Vietnam and to the question of American involvement in the coup.
Erickson, Eric, 1927-1996
Access
Collection open for research.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1984.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical note
Technical writer, United States Army Concept Team in Vietnam, 1963-1964.
Scope and Contents note
Correspondence, memoranda, notes, bulletins, newsletters, clippings, and serial issues, relating to the 1963 coup overthrowing President Ngô Dình Diêm in South Vietnam and to the question of American involvement in the coup.
Ngô, Dình Diêm, 1901-1963.; United States. Army Concept Team in Vietnam.; United States--Armed Forces.; United States--Foreign relations--Vietnam.; United States--Foreign relations.; Vietnam War, 1961-1975.; Vietnam--Foreign relations--United States.; Vietnam--History--Coup d'état, 1963.; Vietnam.
- Preliminary outline of projected book (Box 1)
- Hoover Institution agreement
- Open letter to Ministers' Vietnam Committee
- Responses to open letter
- Original draft and distribution of open letter
- Letters of transmittal of open letter
- Correspondence with Rev. Raymond de Jaegher
- Correspondence (Box 2)
  - SRI
  - Andre Hope
  - E. F. Erickson
  - Ann and Gene Gregory
  - Irene Corbally Kuhn
  - Lt. Col. H. M. Francis
  - Others
- South Vietnam Liberation Front 14-Point Policy (Box 3)
- Personalism and national policy in Vietnam
- Photographs
- Incomplete and undated press clippings
- Press clippings (Box 4)
- Frank Coniff, New York Journal-American
- Gene Gregory, Times of Vietnam
- Time and Newsweek, April 1963-January 1964
- Clippings of exceptional interest
- Special material on Tri Quang
- True report of assassination of Diem and Nhu
- Press clippings (Box 5)
  - June-December 1963
  - Post-coup - and later, 1963, 1964
- Erickson, "The Incredible Buddhist Affair" (Box 6)
- "Assault on an Ally" (Nation's Security)
- Gregory, "What Is Behind the Buddhist Affair"
- Higgins, "A Visit to Xa Loi" (original draft)
- Documents of the Council against Communist Aggression with letter from A. McDowell
- Joint communique - Interministerial Committee and Buddhist Delegation
- "Vietnam Presse" and "Rivarol", (September 1963) (September 1963)
- Congressional Record (Box 7)
  - Vol. 109, no. 112 (Sen. Thurmond insertion of Erickson letter)
  - Vol. 109, no. 127 (Rep. Edna Kelly insertion of Erickson letter)
- Times of Vietnam, June-July 1963 (Box 8)
- Times of Vietnam Magazine (Sunday), June-October 1963
- Times of Vietnam, August 1963 (Box 9)
- Times of Vietnam, September 1963 (Box 10)
- Times of Vietnam, and last issue, October 1963 1 November 1963 (Box 11)
- Saigon Daily News, November 21, 1963-January 31, 1964 (Box 12)
- Saigon Post, January 6-31, 1964 (Box 13)
- Le Journal d'Extreme Orient, September-November 1963; (miscellaneous issues) (Box 14)
- Nouvelles Dimanche, (2 issues)
- Vietnamese papers
- Pacific Stars and Stripes, August-December 1963; (miscellaneous issues) (Box 15)
- Observer, (3 issues)
- U.S. magazines, concerning Vietnam, late 1963 (Box 16)
- USIS Weekly Bulletin, August-October 1963; (miscellaneous issues)
- U.S.O.M. annual report, 1962
- Army Information Digest, January 1963
- Asian magazines, late 1963 (Box 17)